<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no" ?>
<!--<!DOCTYPE labConfiguration SYSTEM "LabConfiguration.dtd">-->
<labConfiguration title="AC Machine" version="3.1">
  <navmenuPhoto>
    <image>~/images/acmachine.jpg</image>
  </navmenuPhoto>
  <labCamera>
    <url>http://openilabs.ilab.uq.edu.au/LabCameras/ACMachine1.htm</url>
  </labCamera>
  <labInfo>
    <text />
    <url />
  </labInfo>
  <configuration>
    <setup id="NoLoad">
      <name>No Load</name>
      <description>
        <p>
          The no load test is used to gather information about the magnetizing branch in the
          induction machine equivalent circuit.  When an induction motor is unloaded, the shaft
          will be running at practically synchronous speed (not quite however, as if it were
          running at synchronous speed no currents would be induced in the rotor windings) and
          therefore a very small, practically zero slip.  This causes the equivalent rotor
          impedance to be very large.  Therefore, the rotor can be considered to be an open
          circuit in this test, and the data obtained from this test will give information on
          the stator and magnetizing impedance.  The data retrieved from this test will be the
          line to line voltage, phase current and power factor of the machine under test.
        </p>
      </description>
    </setup>
    <setup id="FullLoad">
      <name>Full Load</name>
      <description>
        <p>
          This experiment will give information regarding the behavior of the MUT induction
          machine under full load conditions.  In this experiment, rather than having a separate
          mechanical load for the MUT induction machine, the VSD controlled induction machine
          will act as a mechanical load.  The VSD induction machine will act in torque control
          mode to ensure that a counteracting full load torque is applied to the MUT induction
          motor.  The data retrieved from this test will be the line to line voltage, phase
          current and power factor of the machine under test.
        </p>
      </description>
    </setup>
    <setup id="LockedRotor">
      <name>Locked Rotor</name>
      <description>
        <p>
          The locked rotor test is used to calculate the equivalent rotor and stator impedances
          of an induction motor.  When the rotor is stationary, the slip is equal to 1, therefore
          the equivalent rotor resistance is low.  Because the equivalent rotor resistance is low,
          the relatively high impedance magnetizing branch in the equivalent circuit can be
          neglected. Therefore, the information received from the locked rotor test gives
          information on solely the rotor and stator impedances of the induction motor under test.
          The data retrieved from this test will be the line to line voltage, phase current and
          power factor of the machine under test.
        </p>
        <p>
          In this experiment, there is no fixed mechanical locking mechanism to hold the rotor in
          place.  Rather, the shafts of both the variable speed drive (VSD) controlled induction
          motor and the direct on-line machine under test (MUT) are mechanically coupled together.
          The VSD induction motor is speed controlled to 0 rpm.  Therefore, when the MUT is
          connected to the AC supply, the VSD induction machine will supply counteracting torque
          to ensure that the coupled shaft speed remains at 0 rpm, which is equivalent to a locked
          rotor.  The machine under test induction motor is connected to the mains 240V supply via
          a X to X step down transformer.
        </p>
      </description>
    </setup>
    <setup id="SynchronousSpeed">
      <name>Synchronous Speed</name>
      <description>
        <p>
          This experiment is very similar to the no load test.  The major difference is that in
          this experiment, the VSD controlled induction motor (rather than the direct on-line
          machine under test) will bring the shaft speed up to the synchronous speed.  Therefore,
          the VSD induction machine will be providing the rotational losses, and the MUT
          induction machine will be supplying practically only magnetizing current.  The data
          retrieved from this test will be the line to line voltage, phase current and power
          factor of the VSD induction machine.
        </p>
      </description>
    </setup>
    <measurementCount>3</measurementCount>
  </configuration>
  <experimentSpecification>
    <setupId />
  </experimentSpecification>
  <experimentResult>
    <timestamp />
    <title />
    <version />
    <experimentId />
    <unitId />
    <setupId />
    <setupName />
    <voltage />
    <current />
    <powerFactor />
    <speed />
  </experimentResult>
  <resultsApplet>
    <archive></archive>
    <code></code>
  </resultsApplet>
</labConfiguration>
