<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no" ?>
<!--<!DOCTYPE labConfiguration SYSTEM "LabConfiguration.dtd">-->
<labConfiguration title="Synchronous Machine" version="3.2">
  <navmenuPhoto>
    <image>~/images/syncmachine.jpg</image>
  </navmenuPhoto>
  <labCamera>
    <url>http://openilabs.ilab.uq.edu.au/LabCameras/SyncMachine2.htm</url>
  </labCamera>
  <labInfo>
    <text />
    <url />
  </labInfo>
  <configuration>
    <setup id="OpenCircuitVaryField">
      <name>Open-circuit: Voltage versus Field Current</name>
      <description>
        <p>
          The synchronous machine is run at a fixed speed of 1500 RPM.
          The field current is increased from 0.0 amps to 2.8 amps in steps of approximately 100mA.
          At each step, the armature voltage of the synchronous machine is measured.
        </p>
      </description>
    </setup>
    <setup id="OpenCircuitVarySpeed">
      <name>Open-circuit: Voltage versus Motor Speed</name>
      <description>
        <p>
          The synchronous machine is run with a fixed field current of approximately 2.8 amps.
          The speed is increased from 100 RPM to 1500 RPM in steps of 100 RPM.
          At each step, the armature voltage of the synchronous machine is measured.
        </p>
      </description>
    </setup>
    <setup id="ShortCircuitVaryField">
      <name>Short-circuit: Stator Current versus Field Current</name>
      <description>
        <p>
          The stator terminals of the synchronous machine are shorted and the synchronous machine is run at a fixed speed of 1500 RPM.
          The field current is increased from 0.0 amps to 2.8 amps in steps of approximately 100mA.
          At each step, the stator current of the synchronous machine is measured.
        </p>
      </description>
    </setup>
    <setup id="PreSynchronisation">
      <name>Pre-synchronisation: Examining the process</name>
      <description>
        <p>
          Connecting the synchronous machine to the electricity grid (or mains) requires the machine to have the same phase sequence as
          the mains (machine rotating in the correct direction), the same line voltages as the mains, and the line voltages must be
          in phase. There are three main steps required before synchronisation can be achieved:
        </p>
        <p>
          1. The field current of the synchronous machine is increased until the machine voltage is just greater than the mains voltage.
        </p>
        <p>
          2. The speed of the synchronous machine is increased from just below the synchronous speed of 1500 RPM until the machine
          frequency is just greater than the mains frequency.
        </p>
        <p>
          3. The phase of the synchronous machine is compared with the phase of the mains until the phase difference is close to zero.
          The machine speed is increased or decreased slightly to change the phase difference if needed. This step may take some time
          because the frequency of the mains tends to drift. A phase change of 10 to 20 degrees per second between the synchronous machine
          and the mains will generally achieve synchronisation.
        </p>
        <p>
          When the above steps have been carried out, an attempt is made to synchronise the machine to the mains by closing a three phase
          contactor. If synchronisation succeeds, it is held briefly before the contactor is opened and the synchronous machine is
          disconnected from the mains.
        </p>
      </description>
    </setup>
    <setup id="Synchronisation">
      <name>Synchronisation: Operation as a Generator</name>
      <description>
        <p>
          The synchronous machine is synchronised with and connected to the electricity grid.  The speed setpoint is set at 10 RPM above
          synchronous speed to make the machine drive harder and in doing so, operate as a generator and transfer power into the
          electricity grid.
        </p>
        <p>
          The torque setpoint of the DC drive, which is driving the synchronous machine, is increased and measurements are taken. These
          measurements include the synchronous machine field current and phase current, the real and reactive power generated and the
          power factor.
        </p>
        <p>
          As the torque is increased, the synchronous machine field current will need to be decreased to keep the power factor at about
          0.95 although anywhere from 0.8 to 1.0 will be quite alright. Similarly, as the the torque is reduced, the synchronous machine
          field current will need to be increased.
        </p>
        <p>
          The synchronous machine cannot simply be disconnected from the electricity grid while generating power greater than 400 watts.
          This would cause significant arcing across the three phase contactor and damage the equipment. So, the torque setpoint of the
          DC drive is reduced until the generated power is reduced sufficiently. Measurements are again taken as the torque is reduced.
        </p>
      </description>
    </setup>
  </configuration>
  <validation />
  <experimentSpecification>
    <setupId />
  </experimentSpecification>
  <experimentResult>
    <timestamp />
    <title />
    <version />
    <experimentId />
    <unitId />
    <setupId />
    <setupName />
  </experimentResult>
  <resultsApplet>
    <archive></archive>
    <code></code>
  </resultsApplet>
</labConfiguration>
