<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no" ?>
<!--<!DOCTYPE labConfiguration SYSTEM "LabConfiguration.dtd">-->
<labConfiguration title="DC Machine" version="3.1">
  <navmenuPhoto>
    <image>~/images/dcmachine.jpg</image>
  </navmenuPhoto>
  <labCamera>
    <url>http://openilabs.ilab.uq.edu.au/LabCameras/DCMachine1.htm</url>
  </labCamera>
  <labInfo>
    <text />
    <url />
  </labInfo>
  <configuration>
    <setup id="VoltageVsSpeed">
      <name>Generator Voltage versus Speed</name>
      <description>
        <p>
          This experiment looks at the variation of the open circuit armature voltage as the speed
          of the DC motor is varied.  By examining this behaviour, we can understand one part of the
          fundamental relationship between the induced EMF of a DC generator, the speed of the rotor
          and the field current of the rotor (which controls the flux density).  In this experiment,
          the field current is set at a constant value (1A).
        </p>
        <p>
          The speed of the DC motor in this case is controlled by the induction motor, which is
          mechanically coupled to the DC motor shaft.  The speed of this induction machine can be
          precisely controlled using a variable speed drive (VSD) in both the forward and reverse
          directions.
        </p>
        <p>
          The values returned in this experiment are the open circuit armature voltage and the speed
          of the motor in rpm.
        </p>
      </description>
      <paramsTitle>Speed (RPM):</paramsTitle>
      <speedMin>-1500</speedMin>
      <speedMax>1500</speedMax>
      <speedStep>500</speedStep>
    </setup>
    <setup id="VoltageVsField">
      <name>Generator Voltage versus Field Current</name>
      <description>
        <p>
          This experiment examines the variation of the open circuit armature voltage of the DC
          machine as the field current on the rotor is varied.  The amount of current in the rotor
          windings on the DC machine determines the amount of flux within the magnetic system of
          the machine.  The induced EMF of the DC machine is directly proportional to the magnitude
          of flux within the machine as long as the ferromagnetic material within the machine is not
          saturated.  The behaviour of the induced EMF (i.e. open circuit armature voltage) can be
          examined in this experiment by varying the field current, with the speed of the machine
          being held constant by the induction motor at 1500rpm.
        </p>
        <p>
          The field current can only be reduced to a minimum of 50% of its full rated value in this
          test, due to safety concerns about speed run-away at low levels of field current.
        </p>
        <p>
          The values returned in this experiment are the open circuit armature voltage and the
          field current in amps.
        </p>
      </description>
      <paramsTitle>Field (Percent):</paramsTitle>
      <fieldMin>50</fieldMin>
      <fieldMax>100</fieldMax>
      <fieldStep>10</fieldStep>
    </setup>
    <setup id="VoltageVsLoad">
      <name>Voltage Regulation versus Load (Constant Speed)</name>
      <description>
        <p>
          This experiment examines the behaviour of the armature voltage as a function of load.
          The term “load” here can refer to two different aspects.  In the case of the DC machine
          acting as a generator, the term load will refer to an electrical load that the generator
          is supplying with electrical power.  This is of course the usual way that load is referred
          to when discussing voltage regulation.  The armature of a DC machine has non-zero
          resistance which is in series with the load.  So as the electrical load increases, the
          voltage drop across the armature resistance will also increase, leading to a reduction
          in voltage at the armature terminals (for a constant speed, field current and hence EMF).
        </p>
        <p>
          However, in this experiment it is easier to operate the DC machine as a motor, which is
          supplying varying values of torque to the AC machine, which is holding the speed of the
          coupled shafts constant.  These varying values of supplied torque are essentially equivalent
          to varying values of electrical load in the case of the DC machine acting as a generator;
          the only difference is the armature current is in the opposite direction.
        </p>
        <p>
          Therefore, we can still examine the affect of armature current on the armature voltage
          (i.e. voltage regulation) in this case by varying the mechanical load the machine is supplying.
        </p>
        <p>
          The values returned in this experiment are the armature voltage, the speed of the motor in
          rpm and the percentage of load.
        </p>
      </description>
      <paramsTitle>Load (Percent):</paramsTitle>
      <loadMin>0</loadMin>
      <loadMax>80</loadMax>
      <loadStep>10</loadStep>
    </setup>
    <setup id="SpeedVsVoltage">
      <name>Speed versus Applied Voltage (Constant Torque)</name>
      <description>
        <p>
          This experiment examines the behaviour of the DC machine acting as a motor when the applied
          stator voltage is varied.  The DC machine supplies constant torque in this test.
        </p>
        <p>
          The values returned in this experiment are the armature voltage and speed of the motor in rpm.
        </p>
      </description>
      <paramsTitle>Speed (RPM):</paramsTitle>
      <speedMin>-1500</speedMin>
      <speedMax>1500</speedMax>
      <speedStep>500</speedStep>
    </setup>
    <setup id="SpeedVsField">
      <name>Speed versus Field Current</name>
      <description>
        <p>
          In this experiment, the DC machine drive is set to speed control mode (i.e. it is
          operating as a motor) with the supplied armature current constant.  Once this step
          has been performed, the motor is controlled to 750 rpm and the field current is
          changed from its full rated value to 50% of its rated value.  The armature voltage
          is measured for each of these steps.  By examining this experiment’s results, we can
          examine the fundamental DC machine equation which describes the relationship between
          the EMF, field current and speed of the machine, along with the equivalent armature
          circuit of a DC machine.
        </p>
        <p>
          The values returned in this experiment are the speed of the motor in rpm, the field
          current in amps and the armature voltage.
        </p>
      </description>
      <paramsTitle>Field (Percent):</paramsTitle>
      <fieldMin>50</fieldMin>
      <fieldMax>100</fieldMax>
      <fieldStep>10</fieldStep>
    </setup>
  </configuration>
  <validation>
    <vdnSpeed>
      <minimum>-1500</minimum>
      <maximum>1500</maximum>
      <stepMin>100</stepMin>
      <stepMax>1000</stepMax>
    </vdnSpeed>
    <vdnField>
      <minimum>50</minimum>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <stepMin>5</stepMin>
      <stepMax>50</stepMax>
    </vdnField>
    <vdnLoad>
      <minimum>0</minimum>
      <maximum>80</maximum>
      <stepMin>5</stepMin>
      <stepMax>50</stepMax>
    </vdnLoad>
  </validation>
  <experimentSpecification>
    <setupId />
    <speedMin />
    <speedMax />
    <speedStep />
    <fieldMin />
    <fieldMax />
    <fieldStep />
    <loadMin />
    <loadMax />
    <loadStep />
  </experimentSpecification>
  <experimentResult>
    <timestamp />
    <title />
    <version />
    <experimentId />
    <unitId />
    <setupId />
    <setupName />
    <speedMin />
    <speedMax />
    <speedStep />
    <fieldMin />
    <fieldMax />
    <fieldStep />
    <loadMin />
    <loadMax />
    <loadStep />
    <speedVector />
    <fieldVector />
    <voltageVector />
    <loadVector />
  </experimentResult>
  <resultsApplet>
    <archive></archive>
    <code></code>
  </resultsApplet>
</labConfiguration>
